Ok, what's taking place is that when you press down the circuit switch, you're closing the switch which allows the electrons to run all the way through the wires to create this electro magnetic attraction.
You've got your nail here and you notice that this is all free standing right here.
So what you have is this creates this flow of electrons through this wire coils.
Now, then you produce this magnetic field right in here, and thus you have the attraction.
Now you can imagine this.
When this is done, like say this part would be in one town and then you'd have the wires running on a telegraph pole to another town.
Now of course if somebody snipped the wires and this often happened, especially in the old western days when the natives would take it, hear noise from these tall telegraph poles and all of a sudden just snip the wires because they knew again that this contributed somehow to more white people coming into their territories, and this was something that they just obviously did not want.
But the interesting thing about this is if you were the poor person that had the job of setting up the telegraph poles, this was a deadly job because you were definitely killed by natives.
They tried to stop you from putting these things up.
And however it contributed to the advancement of communication where it wasn't just this little letter being delivered, it was a series of beeps and sounds coming through.
Now you can imagine this, using the Morse Code, say that you don't have the opportunity to use a computer on the high seas.
You need to make an SOS signal, the best thing to do is to have flashlight, or something that flashes a light, and this is an international code, however old it may be and not in a lot of use.
That could save your life.
That could get you help.
And I think in one of Tom Hanks in the movie or whatever, he, you've often used light to say, oh, there's a rescue plane coming on Gilligan's Island, often lighting up a bonfire that says SOS on it.
This was the international symbol, and definitely some place that's so remote and so you're trapped some place, very interesting.
If you use the Morse Code and used that simple SOS signal which is deet deet deet dah dah dah deet deet, somebody is going to know you're in trouble.
You can end up being saved, or not saved if you don't learn the Morse Code.